<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The DIY Blogger</title>
    <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The DIY Blogger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.thediyblogger.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to set up Rich Pins on Pinterest (in under 5 minutes)</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-set-up-rich-pins-on-pinterest-in-under-5-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-set-up-rich-pins-on-pinterest-in-under-5-minutes/</guid>
      <description>What are Rich Pins? Rich Pins are essentially a more enhanced version of a regular pin. They will scour your website for extra information, and upgrade the look of your pin with all that wonderful information.
For example, if you have a recipe post, then details about your recipe such as the ingredients can be pulled right into the pin itself.
This has the effect of giving your potential audience more information to look at when they view your pin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to set up a Pinterest Business Account</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-set-up-a-pinterest-business-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-set-up-a-pinterest-business-account/</guid>
      <description>If you have a website that you want to drive insane amounts of traffic to, it is critical that one of the first steps you do is set up a Pinterest Business Account.
If you are new to Pinterest, then the first lesson is to realize that Pinterest is a search engine. It&amp;rsquo;s not a social website (like Twitter or Facebook). It&amp;rsquo;s not just an idea&amp;rsquo;s tool to save your bookmarks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to drive 4x more traffic to your blog with Pinterest SEO</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-drive-4x-more-traffic-to-your-blog-with-pinterest-seo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-drive-4x-more-traffic-to-your-blog-with-pinterest-seo/</guid>
      <description>If you found this page, you probably found it through Pinterest. If you came here via Google, then awesome.
I have been building and designing websites for over 15 years. In that time, most website optimization has been focused on Google and specifically Google SEO. This is normally fine if your website domain has been around for many years, and has established domain authority, or there are a lot of back links coming back into your website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to blog</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-blog/</guid>
      <description>BLOGGING 101 Lets start with the basics of Blogging. The word blog originally comes from the term
web-log (noun): a log (or diary) on the web (internet).  These days, blogging is more about having a regularly updated web site, written in an informal or conversational style. What you are currently reading is a blog.
You may have heard of WordPress, which is one of the most popular blogging platforms available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to SEO and SEM for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/introduction-to-seo-and-sem-for-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/introduction-to-seo-and-sem-for-beginners/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my first post on SEO and SEM.
Many customers feel that if you build a beautiful website, then customers will come pouring through the door.
In reality, there is more to great website design than just pretty fonts, colors, and great imagery.
Users who search for certain keywords on Google will likely find your website only if you rank high on Google, giving you the opportunity to convert those users into potential paying customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build Links to Your Website</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-build-links-to-your-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-build-links-to-your-website/</guid>
      <description>By this time, you should have already optimized your website with the Basic SEO Techniques I outlined in my previous post.
Never fear. There are a few things we can do to get started. But before we do, here is a term we will refer to a lot. &amp;ldquo;Link Juice&amp;rdquo;. Link juice is the amount of &amp;ldquo;juice&amp;rdquo; that one page can send to another.
Global Popularity
You want your website to get as much high quality juice as possible to boost your page rank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why great Web Design is more than just pretty pictures</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/why-great-web-design-is-more-than-just-pretty-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/why-great-web-design-is-more-than-just-pretty-pictures/</guid>
      <description>But, what is a Beautiful Web Design?
Web Design constitutes many aspects. These are the qualities we think are important (and beautiful) when building a website:
 Easy to use Familiarity Balanced Fast to load Easy to read and understand Friendly to the eye  Think about other products you may have used that are not intuitive or easy to use? Why can a two year old child easily figure out how to use an iPad, but they cant figure out the cable remote?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why your business needs a CDN</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/why-your-business-needs-a-cdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/why-your-business-needs-a-cdn/</guid>
      <description>For example, lets say your website was hosted on a server in Atlanta GA. Then, whenever your customer requested your website that did not use a CDN, the request would always come to your server in Atlanta. Local customers may have a decent experience because they are local, but requests from customers on the west coast would have to travel the span of the US. Even worse for global customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to SSL</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/introduction-to-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/introduction-to-ssl/</guid>
      <description>SSL stands for Secure Socket Layer. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a deprecated technology, now replaced by a newer acronym - TLS. TLS stands for Transport Layer Security.
Okay, enough of this gobbledygook! What do all these fancy words mean?!?! In a nutshell, its all about security on the internet.
When you visit your bank website, or these days even Facebook and Google, you will see a lock icon next to the URL in the address bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up DNS</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/setting-up-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/setting-up-dns/</guid>
      <description>You should be familiar with the Address Bar in your browser. It looks something like this:
  Address Bar   When your users go to a URL such as &amp;ldquo;www.drawbuildplay.com&amp;rdquo;, the request will go to a DNS server which routes the request to the correct place where your website is hosted. Think of it like regular mail you send through the post office. You send a letter marked with the recipients address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attributions</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/attributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/attributions/</guid>
      <description> Attributions  Hugo Design: https://html5up.net/massively Hugo Port: https://curtistimson.co.uk/post/project/massively-hugo-theme/ Infrastructure: https://aws.amazon.com/  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT When you visit the Site, we automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we collect information about the individual web pages or products that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check Your Blog&#39;s SEO - Free SEO Analyzer Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/seo-analyzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/seo-analyzer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PinKarma Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/dashboard/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>