<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The DIY Blogger</title>
    <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The DIY Blogger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.thediyblogger.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging Traffic Report - July 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/blogging-traffic-report-july-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/blogging-traffic-report-july-2019/</guid>
      <description>Hi
Welcome to my second traffic report for DrawBuildPlay and TheDIYBlogger.
I have read many posts by other bloggers about their Income reports and Traffic reports. Most of these reports show how successful they have become. What is usually missing is the reports from the start of their journey. Answers to questions like
 How long did it take for you to see traffic and start making six figures from blogging?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging Traffic Report - June 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/blogging-traffic-report-june-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/blogging-traffic-report-june-2019/</guid>
      <description>Hi
This is my first traffic report for DrawBuildPlay and TheDIYBlogger. I have read many other posts by other bloggers about their Income reports and Traffic reports. Most of these reports show how successful they have become. What is usually missing is the reports from the start of their journey. Answers to questions like
 How long did it take for you to see traffic and start making six figures from blogging?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create a winning pin on Pinterest that will get repins</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-create-a-winning-pin-on-pinterest-that-will-get-repins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-create-a-winning-pin-on-pinterest-that-will-get-repins/</guid>
      <description>Target keywords so users can find your pins with Pinterest search Update your board names and board descriptions to create keyword rich boards that actually get searched for by users on Pinterest.
Make sure your pins link to interesting content so that your followers will want to repin it.
Check the description of the pin itself has targeted keywords and uses hashtags. The pin description should align with the board keywords and on page keywords to reinforce what the pin is about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many pins should you pin per day</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-many-pins-should-you-pin-per-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-many-pins-should-you-pin-per-day/</guid>
      <description>Establish your Pinterest presence When starting out with blogging and marketing your blog on Pinterest, the goal should be to fill your boards with relevant and engaging content to help build an audience. Pinterest generally will only start to rank pins in a board once the board has about 20 pins in it. Over time as the board gains more pins and has high engagement, it will rank even better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Branded Pinterest Board Covers in 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-create-branded-pinterest-board-covers-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-create-branded-pinterest-board-covers-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>If you are serious about your blog and marketing your brand on Pinterest, you must create board covers. Here are a few reasons why (even in 2019) board covers are as important as ever.
Branding is important. When a potential follower looks at your boards, would you rather they see a bunch of noisy pin images made by other people, or would you want to control the branding experience and give your boards some love?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unpin a Pin on Pinterest</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/unpin-a-pin-on-pinterest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/unpin-a-pin-on-pinterest/</guid>
      <description>As a Pinterest Business, it is good practice to pin other people&amp;rsquo;s content alongside your content. Sharing is caring, and it gives your audience more information to help them solve their problem.
However, every now and then we may accidentally pin the wrong article. Maybe we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to pin that item. Maybe we wanted to pin it to a different board. Whatever the reason, it is important to know how to unpin a pin on Pinterest so that your boards remain high quality, tidy, and poor quality pins are removed from your board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Keyword Rich Pinterest Board Names to Get More Repins</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-create-keyword-rich-pinterest-board-names-to-get-more-repins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-create-keyword-rich-pinterest-board-names-to-get-more-repins/</guid>
      <description>Choosing Board names is both an art and a skill. Often we as creators think we know what users are searching for, and name our Pinterest boards based on that gut feeling.
The reality is that we often get it completely wrong.
In my previous post, I talked about how to optimize your board name on Pinterest.
In that post, I only briefly touched on making sure your board names were keyword targeted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to protect your blog from legal issues for free</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-protect-your-blog-from-legal-issues-for-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-protect-your-blog-from-legal-issues-for-free/</guid>
      <description>Regardless of what niche your blog is about, it is super important you have some standard legal pages on your blog to protect yourself.
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you are running a business, or are just out there giving free advice, or are a lifestyle blogger. You have an audience who are visiting your blog and reading your content.
If for whatever reason, one of those readers followed your advice but was met with an unfortunate consequence, then they may try to sue you for any damages caused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to find and join Group Boards on Pinterest</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-find-and-join-group-boards-on-pinterest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-find-and-join-group-boards-on-pinterest/</guid>
      <description>What are Pinterest Group Boards Pinterest Group Boards are very similar to regular boards. The main difference is a group board has more than one collaborator.
Some group boards are very open to new contributors, and will have hundreds of members contributing pins. Other group boards may be more strict on who can contribute and may consist of only a handful of contributors. The decision on who can contribute to a group board is left to the owner of the board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Optimize your Pinterest Board Name</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-optimize-your-pinterest-board-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-optimize-your-pinterest-board-name/</guid>
      <description>A Pinterest board name can be up to 100 characters long. But be careful about using all that. I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you why, but first, let&amp;rsquo;s go through how to create a well optimized board name.
Forget Cutesy or Creative! Let&amp;rsquo;s start with those cute or creative board names. You know the ones I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. The boards that you really want to name &amp;ldquo;Food for Thought&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Mr Clean&amp;rdquo;. Sounds fun but it only makes sense to you and will perform very poorly in search.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to evaluate Tailwind Tribes to join</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-evaluate-tailwind-tribes-to-join/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-evaluate-tailwind-tribes-to-join/</guid>
      <description>Have you been pinning for a while now, but just struggling to get any real traffic? Your pins just wont go viral, and the Group Boards have been next to useless for you? Your website traffic is stagnating, and you don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do?
Well, I have news for you. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t already using Tailwinds, then you need to.
Tailwinds is a web application that does a few really awesome things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Optimize your Pinterest Profile for Search</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-optimize-your-pinterest-profile-for-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-optimize-your-pinterest-profile-for-search/</guid>
      <description>Upgrade to a Business Account If you have been using a Pinterest account as an individual, but now want to reuse that account as a brand and increase your reach, then it is critical you upgrade your account to a Business Account. If you are creating a new account, then create the Pinterest profile as a Business Account.
As a business account, it signifies that you are a creator and will likely be producing new content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get more than 30 characters in your Pinterest profile name</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-get-more-than-30-characters-in-your-pinterest-profile-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-get-more-than-30-characters-in-your-pinterest-profile-name/</guid>
      <description>Any serious blogger knows that to succeed on Pinterest you need to treat Pinterest as a Search Engine. Why? Because, Pinterest is a search engine!
So, with that in mind, how to we optimize our Profile name in Pinterest to be keyword rich so it ranks in searches for those keywords? Especially if we have a lame 30 character limit we have to work with, right?
When I first created my account, I was only able to enter The DIY Blogger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to claim your website on Pinterest</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-claim-your-website-on-pinterest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-claim-your-website-on-pinterest/</guid>
      <description>Why should I claim my website on Pinterest? Claiming your website on Pinterest is a very important step on your way to driving crazy traffic to your website. You need to have a claimed (and verified) website before you can apply for Rich Pins on your site. You need a claimed website to also gain invaluable analytics from Pinterest about how pins are doing sending traffic to your website. This data can be used to make critical decisions on how to build and target your future pins to drive more traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to set up Rich Pins on Pinterest (in under 5 minutes)</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-set-up-rich-pins-on-pinterest-in-under-5-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-set-up-rich-pins-on-pinterest-in-under-5-minutes/</guid>
      <description>What are Rich Pins? Rich Pins are essentially a more enhanced version of a regular pin. They will scour your website for extra information, and upgrade the look of your pin with all that wonderful information.
For example, if you have a recipe post, then details about your recipe such as the ingredients can be pulled right into the pin itself.
This has the effect of giving your potential audience more information to look at when they view your pin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to set up a Pinterest Business Account</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-set-up-a-pinterest-business-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-set-up-a-pinterest-business-account/</guid>
      <description>If you have a website that you want to drive insane amounts of traffic to, it is critical that one of the first steps you do is set up a Pinterest Business Account.
If you are new to Pinterest, then the first lesson is to realize that Pinterest is a search engine. It&amp;rsquo;s not a social website (like Twitter or Facebook). It&amp;rsquo;s not just an idea&amp;rsquo;s tool to save your bookmarks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to drive 4x more traffic to your blog with Pinterest SEO</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-drive-4x-more-traffic-to-your-blog-with-pinterest-seo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-drive-4x-more-traffic-to-your-blog-with-pinterest-seo/</guid>
      <description>If you found this page, you probably found it through Pinterest. If you came here via Google, then awesome.
I have been building and designing websites for over 15 years. In that time, most website optimization has been focused on Google and specifically Google SEO. This is normally fine if your website domain has been around for many years, and has established domain authority, or there are a lot of back links coming back into your website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to blog</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-blog/</guid>
      <description>BLOGGING 101 Lets start with the basics of Blogging. The word blog originally comes from the term
web-log (noun): a log (or diary) on the web (internet).  These days, blogging is more about having a regularly updated web site, written in an informal or conversational style. What you are currently reading is a blog.
You may have heard of WordPress, which is one of the most popular blogging platforms available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to SEO and SEM for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/introduction-to-seo-and-sem-for-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/introduction-to-seo-and-sem-for-beginners/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my first post on SEO and SEM.
Many customers feel that if you build a beautiful website, then customers will come pouring through the door.
In reality, there is more to [great website design](https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/why-great-web-design-is-more-than-just-pretty-pictures/) than just pretty fonts, colors, and great imagery.
Users who search for certain keywords on Google or Pinterest will likely find your website only if you rank high on those keywords, giving you the opportunity to convert those users into potential paying customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build Links to Your Website</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-build-links-to-your-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-build-links-to-your-website/</guid>
      <description>By this time, you should have already optimized your website with the Basic SEO Techniques I outlined in my previous post.
Never fear. There are a few things we can do to get started. But before we do, here is a term we will refer to a lot. &amp;ldquo;Link Juice&amp;rdquo;. Link juice is the amount of &amp;ldquo;juice&amp;rdquo; that one page can send to another.
Global Popularity
You want your website to get as much high quality juice as possible to boost your page rank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why great Web Design is more than just pretty pictures</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/why-great-web-design-is-more-than-just-pretty-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/why-great-web-design-is-more-than-just-pretty-pictures/</guid>
      <description>But, what is a Beautiful Web Design?
Web Design constitutes many aspects. These are the qualities we think are important (and beautiful) when building a website:
 Easy to use Familiarity Balanced Fast to load Easy to read and understand Friendly to the eye  Think about other products you may have used that are not intuitive or easy to use? Why can a two year old child easily figure out how to use an iPad, but they cant figure out the cable remote?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why your business needs a CDN</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/why-your-business-needs-a-cdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/why-your-business-needs-a-cdn/</guid>
      <description>For example, lets say your website was hosted on a server in Atlanta GA. Then, whenever your customer requested your website that did not use a CDN, the request would always come to your server in Atlanta. Local customers may have a decent experience because they are local, but requests from customers on the west coast would have to travel the span of the US. Even worse for global customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to SSL</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/introduction-to-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/introduction-to-ssl/</guid>
      <description>SSL stands for Secure Socket Layer. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a deprecated technology, now replaced by a newer acronym - TLS. TLS stands for Transport Layer Security. But you will often hear people talking about SSL or TLS interchangeably.
Okay, enough of this technical gobbledygook! What do all these fancy words mean?!?! In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s all about security on the internet.
When you visit your bank website, or these days even Facebook and Google, you will see a lock icon next to the URL in the address bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up DNS</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/setting-up-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/setting-up-dns/</guid>
      <description>You should be familiar with the Address Bar in your browser. It looks something like this:
  Address Bar   When your users go to a URL such as &amp;ldquo;www.drawbuildplay.com&amp;rdquo;, the request will go to a DNS server which routes the request to the correct place where your website is hosted. Think of it like regular mail you send through the post office. You send a letter marked with the recipients address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Pinterest Audit Checklist</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/free-pinterest-audit-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/free-pinterest-audit-checklist/</guid>
      <description>Let&#39;s fix your Pinterest Strategy struggling to get page views? Have you been at the Pinterest game for a while or just getting started?  You&#39;ve heard all the great things about how Pinterest can drive insane mountains of traffic to your blog in a short time, right. But are you struggling to see your own results? You think you are doing it right but something is just not working!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscription Confirmed</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/subscriptionconfirmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/subscriptionconfirmed/</guid>
      <description>Your subscription to our list has been confirmed.
As a thank you for subscribing to our list, be on the look out for a link to our Free Pinterest Audit Checklist.
The DIY Blogger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attributions</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/attributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/attributions/</guid>
      <description>                            </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT When you visit the Site, we automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we collect information about the individual web pages or products that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returns</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/returns/</guid>
      <description>Our policy lasts 30 days. If 30 days have gone by since your purchase of an annual Pin Karma subscription or a course, unfortunately we can’t offer you a refund or exchange.
Eligibility To be eligible for a refund, you must show that you made a real attempt to apply the strategies presented to you and that you did not see an increase in website traffic as a result. This evidence will be in the form of providing your Pinterest Analytics, Google Analytics, and evidence of the changes you made to your website SEO and/or Pinterest account that were recommended by The DIY Blogger via a paid offering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms of Service</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/terms/</guid>
      <description>OVERVIEW This website is operated by The DIY Blogger. Throughout the site, the terms “we”, “us” and “our” refer to The DIY Blogger, and its parent company DrawBuildPlay, LLC. The DIY Blogger offers this website, including all information, tools and services available from this site to you, the user, conditioned upon your acceptance of all terms, conditions, policies and notices stated here.
By visiting our site and/ or purchasing something from us, you engage in our “Service” and agree to be bound by the following terms and conditions (“Terms of Service”, “Terms”), including those additional terms and conditions and policies referenced herein and/or available by hyperlink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check Your Blog&#39;s SEO - Free SEO Analyzer Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/seo-analyzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/seo-analyzer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PinKarma</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/pinkarma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/pinkarma/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PinKarma Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/dashboard/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>