<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pinterest Tips on The DIY Blogger</title>
    <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/categories/pinterest-tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pinterest Tips on The DIY Blogger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.thediyblogger.com/categories/pinterest-tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Branded Pinterest Board Covers in 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-create-branded-pinterest-board-covers-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-create-branded-pinterest-board-covers-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>If you are serious about your blog and marketing your brand on Pinterest, you must create board covers. Here are a few reasons why (even in 2019) board covers are as important as ever.
Branding is important. When a potential follower looks at your boards, would you rather they see a bunch of noisy pin images made by other people, or would you want to control the branding experience and give your boards some love?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unpin a Pin on Pinterest</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/unpin-a-pin-on-pinterest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/unpin-a-pin-on-pinterest/</guid>
      <description>As a Pinterest Business, it is good practice to pin other people&amp;rsquo;s content alongside your content. Sharing is caring, and it gives your audience more information to help them solve their problem.
However, every now and then we may accidentally pin the wrong article. Maybe we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to pin that item. Maybe we wanted to pin it to a different board. Whatever the reason, it is important to know how to unpin a pin on Pinterest so that your boards remain high quality, tidy, and poor quality pins are removed from your board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Keyword Rich Pinterest Board Names to Get More Repins</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-create-keyword-rich-pinterest-board-names-to-get-more-repins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-create-keyword-rich-pinterest-board-names-to-get-more-repins/</guid>
      <description>Choosing Board names is both an art and a skill. Often we as creators think we know what users are searching for, and name our Pinterest boards based on that gut feeling.
The reality is that we often get it completely wrong.
In my previous post, I talked about how to optimize your board name on Pinterest.
In that post, I only briefly touched on making sure your board names were keyword targeted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to find and join Group Boards on Pinterest</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-find-and-join-group-boards-on-pinterest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-find-and-join-group-boards-on-pinterest/</guid>
      <description>What are Pinterest Group Boards Pinterest Group Boards are very similar to regular boards. The main difference is a group board has more than one collaborator.
Some group boards are very open to new contributors, and will have hundreds of members contributing pins. Other group boards may be more strict on who can contribute and may consist of only a handful of contributors. The decision on who can contribute to a group board is left to the owner of the board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Optimize your Pinterest Board Name</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-optimize-your-pinterest-board-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-optimize-your-pinterest-board-name/</guid>
      <description>A Pinterest board name can be up to 100 characters long. But be careful about using all that. I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you why, but first, let&amp;rsquo;s go through how to create a well optimized board name.
Forget Cutesy or Creative! Let&amp;rsquo;s start with those cute or creative board names. You know the ones I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. The boards that you really want to name &amp;ldquo;Food for Thought&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Mr Clean&amp;rdquo;. Sounds fun but it only makes sense to you and will perform very poorly in search.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to evaluate Tailwind Tribes to join</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-evaluate-tailwind-tribes-to-join/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-evaluate-tailwind-tribes-to-join/</guid>
      <description>Have you been pinning for a while now, but just struggling to get any real traffic? Your pins just wont go viral, and the Group Boards have been next to useless for you? Your website traffic is stagnating, and you don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do?
Well, I have news for you. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t already using Tailwinds, then you need to.
Tailwinds is a web application that does a few really awesome things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Optimize your Pinterest Profile for Search</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-optimize-your-pinterest-profile-for-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-optimize-your-pinterest-profile-for-search/</guid>
      <description>Upgrade to a Business Account If you have been using a Pinterest account as an individual, but now want to reuse that account as a brand and increase your reach, then it is critical you upgrade your account to a Business Account. If you are creating a new account, then create the Pinterest profile as a Business Account.
As a business account, it signifies that you are a creator and will likely be producing new content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get more than 30 characters in your Pinterest profile name</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-get-more-than-30-characters-in-your-pinterest-profile-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-get-more-than-30-characters-in-your-pinterest-profile-name/</guid>
      <description>Any serious blogger knows that to succeed on Pinterest you need to treat Pinterest as a Search Engine. Why? Because, Pinterest is a search engine!
So, with that in mind, how to we optimize our Profile name in Pinterest to be keyword rich so it ranks in searches for those keywords? Especially if we have a lame 30 character limit we have to work with, right?
When I first created my account, I was only able to enter The DIY Blogger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to claim your website on Pinterest</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-claim-your-website-on-pinterest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-claim-your-website-on-pinterest/</guid>
      <description>Why should I claim my website on Pinterest? Claiming your website on Pinterest is a very important step on your way to driving crazy traffic to your website. You need to have a claimed (and verified) website before you can apply for Rich Pins on your site. You need a claimed website to also gain invaluable analytics from Pinterest about how pins are doing sending traffic to your website. This data can be used to make critical decisions on how to build and target your future pins to drive more traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to set up Rich Pins on Pinterest (in under 5 minutes)</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-set-up-rich-pins-on-pinterest-in-under-5-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-set-up-rich-pins-on-pinterest-in-under-5-minutes/</guid>
      <description>What are Rich Pins? Rich Pins are essentially a more enhanced version of a regular pin. They will scour your website for extra information, and upgrade the look of your pin with all that wonderful information.
For example, if you have a recipe post, then details about your recipe such as the ingredients can be pulled right into the pin itself.
This has the effect of giving your potential audience more information to look at when they view your pin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to set up a Pinterest Business Account</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-set-up-a-pinterest-business-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-set-up-a-pinterest-business-account/</guid>
      <description>If you have a website that you want to drive insane amounts of traffic to, it is critical that one of the first steps you do is set up a Pinterest Business Account.
If you are new to Pinterest, then the first lesson is to realize that Pinterest is a search engine. It&amp;rsquo;s not a social website (like Twitter or Facebook). It&amp;rsquo;s not just an idea&amp;rsquo;s tool to save your bookmarks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to drive 4x more traffic to your blog with Pinterest SEO</title>
      <link>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-drive-4x-more-traffic-to-your-blog-with-pinterest-seo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thediyblogger.com/blog/how-to-drive-4x-more-traffic-to-your-blog-with-pinterest-seo/</guid>
      <description>If you found this page, you probably found it through Pinterest. If you came here via Google, then awesome.
I have been building and designing websites for over 15 years. In that time, most website optimization has been focused on Google and specifically Google SEO. This is normally fine if your website domain has been around for many years, and has established domain authority, or there are a lot of back links coming back into your website.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>